JOSE GUERRERO

Software Developer

M: 0423663560 | E: joseguerrerog880@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-guerrerog/ Github: https://github.com/jose-guerrerog/ Potfolio: https://portfolio-pink-seven-87.vercel.app/

SUMMARY

I am a software developer with an Engineering background and over 4 years of commercial experience. My primary expertise is in React.js for front-end development, and I also have a basic foundation in various server-side frameworks, including Django, Node.js, and .Net.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Software Developer

Jun 2024 - Present

Self Employed

- Currently developing a new website for the Eastside Learning Centre, a math tutoring center, using React.js and Next.js
- Automated the sales process for Quality Blinds by leveraging Visual Basic in conjunction with Microsoft Excel
- Enhancing my portfolio to attract more freelance job opportunities

Front-End Developer

Sep 2021 - Apr 2024

Ansarada

- Support in maintaining Monorepo infrastructure and micro frontends using Next.js and Typescript
- Collaborate with UX/UI designers to develop Figma designs for new pages, translating design concepts into seamless and engaging user experiences
- Partner with designers to create reusable React.js components using Storybook, enhancing internal libraries and ensuring consistency across our apps
- Work closely with Product Teams to implement new features for our existing apps using React.js, GraphQL and React Testing Library / Jest for unit testing
- Active participation in Agile sprints, showcasing progress and deliverables every two weeks, fostering transparency and continuous improvement to the whole company



EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration King's Own Institute Jun 2024 - Present Distinction Average

Master of Electrical Engineering University of New South Wales Mar 2015 - Dec 2016 Distinction Average

SKILLS

Tools:

- Typescript ReactJS NextJS •
 Redux Zustand Material UI •
 TailwindCSS Three IS Storyboo
- NodeJS Golang Django
- Jest React Testing Library Cypress
- AWS

Front-End Developer

Medius Health

- Feb 2021 Sep 2021
- Collaborate with designers to translate Figma designs into functional web applications using React/Redux, Typescript, and GraphQL
- Enhance our mobile app by integrating new features with React Native, improving user experience and expanding functionality
- Partner with backend and machine learning engineers to prototype innovative solutions tailored to client needs, fostering cross-functional teamwork
- Develop robust end-to-end and unit tests using Cypress and React Testing Library / Jest
- Provide backend support with Django, handling essential tasks such as creating endpoints

Front-End Developer

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

HiveXchange

- Maintain and enhance our main platform functionalities using React/Redux, Typescript and GraphQL to ensure optimal performance and elevate user engagement
- Migrate legacy AngularJS code to React.js to modernize outdated pages and improve maintainability
- Design and implement an internal web application using React.js,
 Typescript and Material UI to streamline sales operations and boost productivity
- Develop basic API endpoints with Node.is for data integration

Front-End Developer

Mar 2019 - Oct 2019

Macrovue

- Contribute to the upgrade of the main platform using cutting-edge technologies including React/Redux and Django
- Implement Figma designs to develop new features to enhance overall user experience and functionality
- Develop end-to-end and unit tests with Cypress and Jest to ensure robust application and performance
- Integrate GraphQL mutations and queries across both back-end and front-end sides

Junior .Net Developer

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

Adslot

- Engage in numerous web apps projects using Asp.Net MVC, WebAPI, and React/ Redux for rich user experiences
- Develop unit tests using MSTest and Jest for full-stack projects
- Active participation in Agile sprints, embracing all phases of the software development lifecycle for iterative improvement